<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Computational Fluid Dynamics on ｢ALL FICTION｣</title>
    <link>https://godot-bloggy.xyz/categories/computational-fluid-dynamics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Computational Fluid Dynamics on ｢ALL FICTION｣</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 22:55:27 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://godot-bloggy.xyz/categories/computational-fluid-dynamics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Aerodynamics — Viscous-Inviscid Panel Methods (In Progress)</title>
      <link>https://godot-bloggy.xyz/post/panel-methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 22:55:27 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://godot-bloggy.xyz/post/panel-methods/</guid>
      <description>References  Drela, Mark. Flight Vehicle Aerodynamics. The MIT Press, 2014. Drela, Mark and Giles, M. B. Viscous-Inviscid Analysis of Transonic and Low Reynolds Number Airfoils. AIAA Journal, 1986. Katz, Joseph and Plotkin, Allen. Low-Speed Aerodynamics - 2nd Edition. Cambridge University Press, 2001.  Viscous-Inviscid Panel Methods Boundary element methods express the solution of some PDE on a volume by reducing it to the specification on a surface. Panel methods in aerodynamics are special cases of such expressions, in which the governing equation is Laplace&amp;rsquo;s equation in a uniform flow in the case of a steady, inviscid, incompressible fluid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gradient-Based Optimisation — Discrete Direct and Adjoint Methods (In Progress)</title>
      <link>https://godot-bloggy.xyz/post/opt-problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 22:55:27 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://godot-bloggy.xyz/post/opt-problems/</guid>
      <description>Optimisation problems are becoming a big meme, so let&amp;rsquo;s address some of the general ideas and how to compute them for discretised systems of equations.
Problem Description Let the vector $\mathbf p_i \in \mathbb R^n$ be the state variable at the $i$th iteration, and the function as a matrix $\mathbf R \in \mathbb R^m \times \mathbb R^n$ which needs to be solved.
$$ \mathbf R(\mathbf p) = \mathbf 0 $$</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computational Fluid Dynamics — CFDPython</title>
      <link>https://godot-bloggy.xyz/post/cfd-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 16:54:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://godot-bloggy.xyz/post/cfd-python/</guid>
      <description>This &amp;lsquo;notebook&amp;rsquo; consists of my run-through of Prof. Lorena Barba&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;12 steps to Navier-Stokes&amp;rdquo; course, because I admit I have a problem with fluids. The Navier-Stokes equations that will be solved in this notebook are the following in conservative form:
$$ \frac{\partial \rho}{\partial t} + \nabla \cdot \left(\rho V\right) = 0 $$
$$ \frac{\partial (\rho\vec V)}{\partial t} + \nabla \cdot \left(\rho ~\vec V \otimes \vec V + p\hat I \right) = \rho \vec g + \nabla \cdot \hat \tau + \vec f$$</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meshing Techniques — Cambered Airfoil</title>
      <link>https://godot-bloggy.xyz/post/meshing-airfoil/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 22:55:50 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://godot-bloggy.xyz/post/meshing-airfoil/</guid>
      <description>Meshing is a crucial process in obtaining accurate results for various simulations across different fields. In computational fluid dynamics, various meshing techniques are used in grid generation for 2D analyses of airfoils. Some nice run-throughs exist on YouTube, but they mostly deal with symmetric airfoils such as the beloved NACA 0012. I&amp;rsquo;ll attempt generating preliminary meshes over a cambered airfoil in this post and probably write a project once I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to perform flow analyses with accurate results.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
